现在我调动步兵师
All right, I'm moving my infantry division...
和指环王中的半兽人兵团
...augmented by a battalion of orcs from Lord of the Rings.
我们从侧翼包夹了田纳西的志愿兵
We flank the Tennessee volunteers
而在北方 我们又一次赢得了葛底斯堡战役
and the North once again wins the Battle of Gettysburg.
没这么容易
Not so fast.
别忘了 南方还有两个步兵师
Remember, the South still has two infantry divisions.
再加上超人和哥斯拉
Plus Superman and Godzilla.
半兽人是魔法部队 超人最怕魔法
No, no, no. Orcs are magic. Superman is vulnerable to magic.
更别提...
Not to mention
哥斯拉早已被伊利诺伊骑兵和绿巨人消灭
you already lost Godzilla to the Illinois Cavalry and Hulk.
为什么不让罗伯特・李将军冲锋?
Why don't you just have Robert E. Lee charge the line
罗伯特・李 南北战争时期南军统帅
他可以带上湿婆和格涅沙
with Shiva and Ganesh?
- 可以点餐了吗? - 稍等 宝贝
-You guys ready to order? -Hang on,honey.
湿婆和格涅沙
Shiva and Ganesh,
印度教之神? 对抗整个北部联军?
the Hindu gods,against the entire Union army?
还有半兽人
And orcs.
我稍候再来
I'll be back.
不好意思
Excuse me.
象头神格涅沙擅长清除障碍 湿婆是毁灭之神
Ganesh is the Remover of Obstacles and Shiva is the Destroyer.
当硝烟散尽之时
When the smoke clears
林肯将会一边说着印地语 一边喝南方的薄荷饮料
Abraham Lincoln will be speaking Hindi and drinking mint juleps.
我老板说你们要么点餐 要么就给他滚蛋
All right,my boss says you have to either order or leave and never come back.
对于做了一早上的举重和有氧锻炼 冒着甜美气息的我
What do you recommend for someone who worked up a man-sized appetite
有什么推荐菜式?
from a morning of weight training and cardio funk?
洗澡
A shower.
我要个奶酪拼盘
I'll take the Heart Smart platter.
好 谢谢你 谢尔顿呢?
All right,thank you,and Sheldon?
我们没在这里吃过
We don't eat here.
不知道什么好吃
I don't know what's good.
都很好吃
Well,it's all good.
概率上不太可能
Statistically unlikely.
就点一个汉堡
Just get a hamburger.
你喜欢汉堡
You like hamburgers.
我喜欢我们常去的那家汉堡店的汉堡
I like the hamburgers where we usually have hamburgers.
不能假定我也喜欢这里的汉堡
You can't make the assumption that I'll like the hamburgers here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
给他一个汉堡
Give him a hamburger.
好吧 哪种?
All right,which one?
经典汉堡 农家汉堡
The Classic Burger,the Ranch House Burger,
烧烤汉堡 柯比汉堡?
the Barbecue Burger,or the Kobe Burger?
能不能去大胖汉堡店?
Can't we just go to Big Boy?
他们只有一种汉堡 大胖汉堡
They only have one burger... the Big Boy.
烧烤汉堡跟大胖汉堡挺像的
Well,the Barbecue Burger is like the Big Boy.
对不起 既然世上已经有大胖汉堡
Excuse me, in a world that already includes a Big Boy
为什么我们要满足于像大胖汉堡呢?
why would I settle for something like a Big Boy?
因为你不在大胖汉堡店!
Because you're not at Big Boy!
好吧 那我要烧烤汉堡
Fine,I'll have the Barbecue Burger.
我也要这个
Make it two.
大胖汉堡店的侍应从不冲被人嚷嚷
Waitresses don't yell at you at Big Boy.
- 嘿 莱纳德 - 你们好
-Hey,Leonard. -Hi,guys.
你好 莱斯利
Hey. Hi,Leslie.
- 不知道你们会来这里吃饭 - 确实不会
I didn't know you ate here. We don't.
这次是很不愉快的例外
This is a disturbing aberration.
莱斯利 他是佩妮
Leslie,this is Penny.
她住在我和谢尔顿的对面
She lives across the hall from Sheldon and me.
她走在美的光彩中 像夜晚
And walks in quiet beauty like the night.
诗人拜伦的名句
霍华德 我已经说了 别这样
Howard,I've asked you not to do that.
莱斯利和我在同个大学做研究
Leslie and I do research together at the university.
哇 女科学家
Oh,wow,a girl scientist.
没胸 只好多长点大脑
Yep,come for the breasts,stay for the brains.
碰见你太好了
So,I'm glad I ran into you.
物理系弦乐四重奏还缺一个大提琴
The Physics Department string quartet needs a new cellist.
埃利奥特・王怎么啦?
What happened to Elliot Wong?
他调到高能辐射课题组了
He switched over to high-energy radiation research
发生一些小意外 其他团员怕坐他身边被辐射
had a little mishap,and now the other guys are uncomfortable sitting next to him.
你来不来?
So are you in?
当然来
Yeah,sure,why not?
太好了 周二去你那里彩排
Great,we rehearse on Tuesdays at your place.
为什么去我那里?
Why at my place?
能源部说我们原来 排练的地方现在是危险区
Yeah,Department of Energy said our regular space is kind of a hot zone.
很高兴见到你
Nice meeting you.
我也是
Yeah,you,too.
莱纳德 不知道你会拉大提琴
Leonard,I didn't know you played the cello.
是啊 我父母觉得给我取名莱纳德
Yeah,my parents felt that naming me Leonard
把我扔进大学先修班
and putting me in Advanced Placement classes
还不够把我搞倒
wasn't getting me beaten up enough.
你喜欢音乐吗? 我会学架子鼓
If you're into music, I happen to be a human beatbox.
真的?
Really?
其实我不是太喜欢音乐
I'm actually not that into music.
你那个朋友不错  你们俩是不是有点情况?
So,hey,your friend's really cute. Anything going on with you two?
莱斯利?
L - Leslie?
没有 怎么可能?
No,no. What,are you kidding?
他约过她一次 不过尴尬地失败了
He asked her out once. It was an embarrassing failure.
多谢 谢尔顿
Thank you,Sheldon.
噢 对不起
Oh,I'm sorry.
这个需要保密吗?
Was that supposed to be a secret?
哦 太可惜了
Aw,that's too bad.
你们本可以做一对甜蜜情侣
You guys'd make a cute couple.
我的天
Oh,dear.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
她没问我点什么
She didn't take my order.
她怎么问你?
How can she take your order
你紧张得连话都不会说
when you're too neurotic to talk to her?
尽管如此 这将反映在她的小费上
Nevertheless,this will be reflected in her tip.
佩妮说"你们本可以做一对甜蜜情侣" 什么意思?
What did Penny mean,"You'd make a cute couple?"
我想她的意思是 你们两个在一起可以组成情侣
Well,I assume she meant the two of you together would constitute a couple
并且令其他人觉得你们甜蜜
that others might consider cute.
另一个不太可能的解释是
An alternate and somewhat less likely interpretation
你们可以制造一对情侣
is that you could manufacture one.
例如 "快看 莱纳德和莱斯利所生的高德法布夫妻
As in,"Oh,look,Leonard and Leslie made Mr.and Mrs.Goldfarb.
是不是很可爱?"
Aren't they adorable?"
如果佩妮不知道莱斯利拒绝过我
If Penny didn't know that Leslie had turned me down,
那么这一句的所指将十分明确
then it would unambiguously mean
即 她(佩妮)认为我应该追她(莱斯利)
that she,Penny,thought I should ask her,Leslie,out
表明她(佩妮)对于我 追求她(佩妮)并无兴趣
indicating that she,Penny, had no interest in me asking her,Penny,out.
但由于她知道我追过莱斯利
But,because she did know that I had asked Leslie out
并且她(莱斯利)已经拒绝我
and that she,Leslie,had turned me down,
那么她(佩妮)可能只是安慰我
then she,Penny,could be offering consolation.
"真可惜 你们本来 可以做一对甜蜜情侣..."
"That's too bad, you would have made a cute couple..."
并且暗想 "很好 莱纳德还是单身"
but while thinking:"Good, Leonard remains available."
你很幸运 莱纳德
You're a lucky man,Leonard.
怎么说?
How so?
听你说话的人
You're talking to one of the three men
是西半球仅有的三个 能跟得上你思维的人之一
in the western hemisphere capable of following that train of thought.
那么 你怎么看?
Well,what do you think?
我只是说我能跟上 不代表我有兴趣
I said I could follow it. I didn't say I care.
宇宙是个大火炉 *
Our whole universe was in a hot,dense state
140亿年前大爆炸 哦稍等 *
Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait!
地球开始冷却 *
The Earth began to cool
生物开始繁衍 尼安得特尔人发明工具*
The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools
我们建造墙瓦 我们创造金字塔 *
We built the Wall  We built the pyramids
数学 科学 历史  揭露奥秘*
Math,Science,History,unraveling the mystery
就从宇宙大爆炸开始! *
That all started with a big bang
磅
Bang!
《生活大爆炸》
第一季  第05集
The.Hamburger.Postulate
我很欣赏你的指法
I admire your fingering.
谢谢
Thank you.
也许你可以在我的"乐器"上演练一下
Maybe sometime you can try that on my instrument.
- 晚安兄弟 练得不错 - 谢谢
Good night,guys. Good job. Thanks.
下周见
See you next week.
挺好玩的 莱斯利 多谢你叫上我
That was fun,Leslie. Thanks for including me.
不客气
You're welcome.
如果你有兴趣
If you're up for it
我们可以练一下中间部分
we could practice that middle section again.
当然好
Sure,why not?
说说清楚比较好 你知不知道我留下来陪你加练
Just so we're clear,you understand that me hanging back to practice with you
是一个铺垫 为了让你知道我是潜在性对象
is a pretext for letting you know that I'm sexually available.
真的?
Really?
是的 我随时可以
Yeah,I'm good to go.
我以为你对我没兴趣
I thought you weren't interested in me.
那是在看到你摆弄两腿之间 那块优雅的木头之前
That was before I saw you handling that beautiful piece of wood between your legs.
你是指大提琴?
You mean my cello?
不 那是一个明显下流的双关
No,I mean the obvious,crude,double entendre.
我在勾引你
I'm seducing you.
不是吧
No kidding.
怎么说呢? 我是有激情的冲动型女人
What can I say? I'm a passionate and impulsive woman.
你说呢?
So how about it?
这个 呃...
Gee. Uh...
因为那个侍应生?
Is it the waitress?
佩妮?
Penny?
她怎么了?
What about her?
你看她的时候瞳孔放大
I thought I saw your pupils dilate when you looked at her.
这表明有性吸引力 除非是海洛因成瘾反应
Which,unless you're a heroin addict, points to sexual attraction.
我早餐吃了一个含罂粟籽的百吉饼
Well,I did have a poppy seed bagel for breakfast.
可能导致阿片碱尿检阳性
Which could cause a positive urine test for opiates
但肯定不至于扩大瞳孔
but certainly not dilate my pupils.
所以...我不知道为什么要说起这个
So I guess there was no point in bringing it up.
你和那个侍应生
You and the waitress then.
没有 没有
No... no.
我和佩妮之间没什么
There's nothing going on between Penny and me.
所以你可以建立性关系咯?
So you're open to a sexual relationship?
可以可以 我想
Yeah,yeah,I guess I am.
好
Good.
很好
Yeah,it is. It is good.
要现在就开始?
Did you want to start now?
演完这一章吧
Why don't we finish the section first?
好的
Oh,okay.
音乐前戏 不错
A little musical foreplay. Terrific.
- 我准备好了 - 我也是
I'm g-good to go. Me,too.
谢尔顿 怎么了?
Oh,hey,Sheldon. What's going on?
我需要符号学方面的帮助
I need your opinion on a matter of semiotics.
什么?
I'm sorry?
符号学 研究符号和象征
Semiotics. The study of signs and symbols.
是语言学基本理论的分支
It's a branch of philosophy related to linguistics.
亲爱的 我知道你以为自己在解释
Okay,sweetie, I know you think you're explaing yourself
其实你真的没有
but you're really not.
跟我来
Just come with me.
怎样?
Well?
什么怎样?
Well,what?
什么意思?
What does it mean?
得了 你上过大学的
Oh,come on,you went to college.
是的 我那是才11岁上
Yes,but I was 11.
好吧 是这样
All right,look,
门把手上挂条领带 意思是里面的人不想被打扰
a tie on the doorknob usually means someone doesn't want to be disturbed
因为...他们 在忙活
because,they're... you know,gettin' busy.
就是说莱纳德跟个女孩在房间里?
So you're saying Leonard has a girl in there?
不然就是他丢了衣架
Well,either that or he's lost his tie rack
并且真的疯狂地喜欢布莱恩・亚当斯
and gotten really into Bryan Adams.
莱纳德 你这了不起的野兽!
Oh,Leonard,you magnificent beast.
我们真不该站这了
We really shouldn't be standing here.
太尴尬了
This is very awkward.
不会吧 莱纳德以前也带女孩回来过 是吧?
Oh,come on,Leonard's had girls over before,right?
有的 但通常要计划 求爱 并且提前通知...
Oh,yes,but there's usually planning, courtship,advance notice...
就像上次 我才有时间预订去北极看日食的旅行
Last time,I was able to book a cruise to the Arctic to see a solar eclipse.
就应为你室友要做爱 你就得离开这个国家?
You had to leave the state because your roommate was having sex?
不是一定要 时间上完全是个巧合
I didn't have to. The dates just happened to coincide.
你知道里面那是谁吗?
So,do you know who's in there?
里面有莱纳德
Well,there's Leonard.
跟他在一起的要么是莱斯利・温克 要不就是30年代的黑帮
And he's either with Leslie Winkle or a 1930s gangster.
他真不错
Hmm,good for him.
恭喜莱纳德
Good for Leonard.
好吧 晚安
Okay,g'night.
等等 别走!
No,no,wait,hold on.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
我不知道这种情况下标准做法是什么
I don't know what the protocol is here.
我该留下来? 还是出去?
Do I stay? Do I leave?
他们出来时 要递上提神饮料吗?
Do I wait to greet them with a refreshing beverage?
谢尔顿 你问错人了
Gee,Sheldon,you're asking the wrong girl.
我通常在领带的另一边
I'm usually on the other side of the tie.
你好 莱纳德?
Hi,Leonard?
是我 谢尔顿
It's me,Sheldon...
我在客厅
In the living room.
我就想告诉你 我看到领带了
I just... I wanted you to know I saw the tie.
消息收到
Message received.
不客气
You're welcome.
继续吧
Carry on.
向莱斯利问好
Give my best to Leslie.
大胖汉堡...
Big Boy...
有人动过我的写字板
Someone touched my board.
天啊 我的写字板!
Oh,God,my board!
莱纳德! 莱纳德!
Leonard! Leonard!
怎么了?
Hey,what's the matter?
有人改过我的公式!
My equations,someone's tampered with my equations.
- 你确定? - 很确定!
Are you sure? Of course I'm sure.
看看量子色动力学的贝塔函数
Look at the beta function of quantum chromodynamics.
符号被改了!
The sign's been changed.
对哦
Oh,yeah.
那不正好解决了你的问题吗?
But doesn't that fix the problem you've been having?
你疯了吗? 你傻了吗?
Are you insane? Are you out of your mind?
你...哦 瞧瞧
Are you... hey,look.
这正好解决了我的问题
That fixes the problem I've been having.
不客气
You're welcome.
你干的?
Youdid this?
我起来喝水的时候发现的
Yeah,I noticed it when I got up to get a glass of water.
我改了 这样就能证明夸克
So I fixed it and now you can show that quarks
在高能状态下是渐进自由的
are asymptotically free at high energies.
很赞吧?
Pretty cool,huh?
"赞"?
"Cool"?
我要去实验室了
Listen,I've got to get to the lab.
昨晚很棒 谢了
Thanks for a great night.
谢谢 上班见
Thank you. I'll see you at work.
等等!
Hold on. Hold on!
怎么?
What?
谁说你可以碰我的写字板的?
Who told you you could touch my board?
没人
No one.
我不会去你家碰你的写字板
Yeah,I don't come into your house and touch your board.
我的板子上没有错误的公式啊
There are no incorrect equations on my board.
你真是...
Oh,that is so...
太...
so...
对不起 我要走了
I'm sorry,I've got to run.
如果你想好形容词 短信发我
If you come up with an adjective,text me.
不体谅
Inconsiderate.
就是这个词 "不体谅"
That is the adjective,"inconsiderate. "
你就算一直瞪着写字板 谢尔顿
You can stare at your board all day,Sheldon.
她还是对的
She's still going to be right.
我不是在瞪 我在思索
I'm not staring, I'm mulling.
- 嘿 莱纳德 - 嗨
Oh,hey,Leonard. Oh,hi.
那么...
So...
如何呀?
...how's it going?
还好
Pretty good.
只是还好?
Just pretty good?
我觉得是很好呀
I'd think you were doing very good.
"还" "很"只是描述"好"的变化程度 并没有客观的范围
Pretty,very... there's really no objective scale for delineating variations of "good. "
你为什么这么问?
Why do you ask?
小鸟告诉我昨晚你跟莱斯利勾搭上了
Well,a little bird told me that you and Leslie hooked up last night.
谢尔顿!
Sheldon!
你是来真的? 你喜欢她吗?
So,is it serious? Do you like her?
我不...
I don't...
那是两个不同的问题
Th-th-that's really two different questions.
我不是...
Uh,I'm not...
谢尔顿 我们得走了!
Sheldon,we have to go!
对于一个刚进行过性交的人来说 你真是出奇的紧张啊
Boy,you're wound awfully tight for a man who's just had sexual intercourse.
好吧 下次再说吧 不过我真为你高兴 莱纳德
All right,well,I'll talk to you later, but I am so happy for you,Leonard.
谢谢
Thank you.
她为我高兴是什么意思?
What did she mean she's happy for me?
她高兴我现在有伴了?
Is she happy that I'm seeing someone?
还是因为我开心所以她高兴?
Or is she happy because she thinks that I'm happy?
如果一个人喜欢别人 就会希望那人开心吧?
Because anyone who cared for someone would want them to be happy.
就算那人开心的理由让前者伤心
Even if the reason for their happiness made the first person unhappy.
因为开心的后者
Because the second person,though happy,
就不能跟前者成为情侣了
is now romantically unavailable to the first person.
你意识到我可能要跟你的性交对象 分享诺贝尔奖吗?
Do you realize I may have to share a Nobel Prize with your booty call?
你知道吗?
You know what?
我真可笑
I'm being ridiculous.
谁在乎佩妮怎么想?
Who cares what Penny thinks?
莱斯利是个很棒的女孩
Leslie is a terrific girl.
漂亮
She's attractive.
我们喜欢对方
We like each other.
她还超级聪明
She's extremely intelligent...
哪有很聪明
She's not that intelligent.
她修正了你的方程式
She fixed your equation.
- 那是走运 - 你根本不相信运气这种事
She got lucky. You don't believe in luck.
我不信 但她也可以走运
I don't have to believe in it for her to be lucky.
不管怎样 我现在有机会和莱斯利发展一段真正的恋情
Regardless,I have a chance at a real relationship with Leslie.
我不会就这么放弃的
I'm not going to pass that up for some
而只为了跟一个可能希望 也可能不希望我和别人开心的女人
hypothetical future of happiness with a woman
拥有一段假想的幸福未来
who may or may not want me to be happy,
而现在 那个别人已经让我很开心了
with a woman who is currently making me happy.
- 莱纳德...  - 啊?
Leonard... Yeah?
我还是没兴趣
I still don't care.
- 嗨 莱斯利 - 小心 莱纳德
Hey,Leslie. Careful,Leonard.
液氮 华氏零下320度
Liquid nitrogen,320 degrees below zero.
你为什么要砸碎速冻香蕉?
Why are smashing a flash-frozen bana?
我有一碗麦片 又找不到刀子
Because I got a bowl of Cheerios and I couldn't find a knife. Oh.
那么...
So anyway...
你好
Hello.
你在干嘛?
Uh,what are you doing?
跟你亲近一下
Just extending the intimacy.
想溜进辐射实验室
Hey,do you want to slip over to the radiation lab
一起洗个去污澡吗?
and share a decontamination shower?
好吧 你觉得我们俩之间发生了什么事?
Okay,uh,what exactly do you think's going on between us?
不知道 不过我可能就要知道那香蕉什么感觉了
I'm not sure,but I think I'm about to discover how the bana felt.
莱纳德 我们都不是神经学家
Listen,Leonard,neither of us are neuroscientists
但是都了解性的生物化学原理
but we both understand the biochemistry of sex.
脑中的多巴胺在神经键中释放 造成快感
I mean,dopamine in our brains is released across synapses,causing pleasure.
在老鼠大脑里插入电极 再给它个高潮按键
You stick electrodes in a rat's brain, give him an orgasm button,
它会一直按着那个键直到死
he'll push that thing until he starves to death.
谁不会呢?
Well,who wouldn't?
我们跟老鼠的区别就在于
Well,the only difference between us and the rat
我们不能在我们视丘下部置入电极
is that you can't stick an electrode in our hypothalamus.
所以你就派上用场了
That's where you come in.
很高兴能起到作用
Yeah,well,I'm just glad to be a part of it.
那么现在如何?
So what happens now?
不知道你性欲多强烈 但我到新年之前应该都够了
Well,I don't know about your sex drive, but I'm probably good till New Year's.
好吧 谢谢
Oh. Okay. Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你想定下新年的计划吗?
You want to make plans for New Year's?
莱纳德 拜托了 你噎到我了
Whoa,Leonard,please. You're smothering me.
抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
瞧瞧
Hey,look.
这不是种马博士吗!
It's Dr. Stud!
什么博士?
Dr. What?
博客界的人都因为你跟莱斯利
The blogosphere is a-buzzin'with news of you
奏响的嘿休小夜曲兴奋不已呢!
and Leslie Winkle makingeine kleine bang-bangmusik.
这事怎么传上网的?
What? How did it get on the Internet?
我放上去的
I put it there.
你怎么知道的?
Well,how did you know about it?
小鸟告诉我们的
A little bird told us.
很明显 你是头野兽
Apparently,you are a magnificent beast.
那倒是真的
That part's true.
我想我以前误解这家餐厅了
You know, I think I may have misjudged this restaurant.
不是吧
No kidding.
我不想冒险
I don't want to go out on a limb,
但我可能找到了新的周二汉堡包
but I think we may be looking at my new Tuesday hamburger.
原来的周二汉堡会很伤心的
Your old Tuesday hamburger will be so brokenhearted.
早想到了
Way ahead of you.
我想把"大胖汉堡"挪到周四
I was thinking of moving Big Boy to Thursdays,
放弃"汤植园" (一家自助餐厅)
and just dropping Souplantation.
- 真的? - 对
Really? Yeah.
我总是搞不懂这名字
The name always confused me anyway.
汤植园
Souplantation.
汤可没法种植出来
You can't grow soup.
如何呀?
So,how's everything?
棒极了
Mmm! Terrific.
你会很高兴的看到 我打算每周二晚上都来这
You'll be happy to know that I plan to come here every Tuesday night
在可预见的将来
for the foreseeable future.
真的? 太好了~
Really? Oh,yay!
如果要永久订下这张台 要跟谁谈?
Who do I speak to about permanently reserving this table?
不知道 心理医生吧?
Um... I don't know... a psychiatrist?
嘿
So,hey
你和莱斯利如何?
how are things with you and Leslie?
说实话 我认为是没戏了
Oh,to be honest, I don't think it's going to work out.
啊 太糟了
Oh. Oh,that's too bad.
别担心
Well,hey,don't worry.
我相信会有合适你的人的
I'm sure there's someone out there who's just right for you.
她那么说什么意思?
What did she mean by that?!
是普通的安慰语?
Was that just a generic platitude,
还是吸引我注意的微妙暗示?
or was that a subtle bid for attention?
你知道这个比大胖汉堡强的原因吗?
You know why this hamburger surpasses the Big Boy?
这是单层的 大胖汉堡是双层
This is a single-decker hamburger, whereas the Big Boy is a double-decker.
这个汉堡的肉 面包和调料的比例 更令人满意
This has a much more satisfying meat-to-bun-to-condiment ratio.
你在听我说话吗?
Are you even listening to me?
当然 在听
Of course,I'm listening.
废话+关于佩妮无望的幻想+废话
Blah,blah,hopeless Penny delusion,blah,blah,blah.
那好吧
Okay,then.
你知道 汤的配料是可以种植的
You know,you can grow the ingredients for soup.